Guide to the Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Writings, 1926-1995
  - Subseries V.2: Articles and Essays, 1926-1995
    - "Movimenti Filosofici del Rinascimento," 1950 (Box 121)
    - "The Myth of Renaissance Atheism and the French Tradition of Free Thought," 1951-1973 (Box 121)
    - "Der Nachlass Ludwig Bertalots," 1965 (Box 121)
    - "Neoplatonism and Renaissance Thought", (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "Neoplatonismo e Rinascimento," 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 121)
    - "Niccolo Perotti ed I Suoi Contributi Alla Storia Dell' Umanesimo," 1981 (Box 122)
    - "Nuova Colelzione di Testi Umanistici Inedito o Rari," 1987-1992 (Box 122)
    - "Nuove Fonte per la Medicina Salernitana del Secola XII," 1957-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "Der Objektivitätsbegriff in der Transcendentalen Deduktion," 1920s (Box 122)
    - "Un Opuscolo Sconsciuto di Cencio de'Rustici Dedicato a Bornio da Sala: LaTraduzione del Dialogo 'De Virtute" Atribuito a Platone," 1975-1982, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "Orationem Periclis apud Thucydidem," 1931 (Box 122)
    - "E Ora Abbiamo Ritrovato Kristeller a New York: 'Vi Racconto Come Andola Mia Avventura,'" 1994 (Box 122)
    - "The Origin and Development of the Language of Italian Prose," 1950 (Box 122)
    - "Paduan Averroism and Alexandrianism in the Light of Recent Studies," 1957-1958 (Box 122)
    - "Il Pensiero del Rinscimento: Problemi e Ricerche," 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "Il Petrarca, L'Umanesimo e la Scolastica," 1956 (Box 122)
    - "Il Petrarca Nella Storia Degli Studi," 1997 (Box 122)
    - Philosophical Essay, undated (Box 122)
    - "A Philosophical Treatise from Bologna Dedicated to Guido Covalcanti: Magister Jacobus de Pistorio and His "Quaestio de Felicitate," 1955 (Box 122)
    - "Philosophy and Humanism in the Renaissance," 1961-1965 (Box 122)
    - "Philosophy and Medicine in Medieval and Renaissance Italy," 1955-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "The Platonic Academy of Florence," 1958-1960, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - Polak Preface, 1987-1997 (Box 122)
    - "Il Posto di Niccolo Perotti nella Storia dell'Umanesimo," 1980-1981 (Box 122)
    - "Il Problema del Rinascimento nella Storia del Pensiero Filisophico," 1976-1979 (Box 122)
    - "Problems of Historical Knowledge," 1954-1960, (3 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "Punto di Riferimento," 1982 (Box 122)
    - The Pursuit of Holiness-- Comments, 1972-1973 (Box 122)
    - "Quando La Filosofia e Solo Ideologia," 1994 (Box 122)
    - "Recollections of My Life," 1995 (Box 122)
    - "Relazione Sulla Edizione di Scrittori Umanisti," 1953 (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Humanism and Classical Antiquity" in Renaissance Humanism, 1982-1986 (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Humanism and Its Lessons," 1978 (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Humanism and Its Significance" (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Philosophy and the Medieval Tradition," 1960-1968 (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Platonism," 1956-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 122)
    - "The Renaissance: A Reconsideration of the Theories and Interpretations of the Period," 1959-1960 (Box 122)
    - "Renaissance Thought and the Arts"-- Expanded Edition, 1990 (Box 123)
    - "Rhetoric in Medieval and Renaissance Culture," 1983 (Box 123)
    - "Il Rinascimento Nella Storia del Pensiero Filosofico," 1979 (Box 123)
    - "The Scholastic Background of Marsilio Ficino: With an Edition of Unpublished Texts," 1944 (Box 123)
    - "The School of Salerno: Its Developments and Its Contribution to the History of Learning," 1945 (Box 123)
    - "The Search for Medieval and Renaissance Manuscripts," 1974-1976 (Box 123)
    - "Sebastiano Salvini: A Florentine Humanist and Theologian, and a Member of Marsilio Ficino's platonic Academy," 1961 (Box 123)
    - "Some New Additions to the Correspondence of Guarino of Verona," 1965-1967 (Box 123)
    - "Some Original Letters and Autograph Manuscripts of Marsilio Ficino," 1963-1965, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "Die Stellung der Ethik im Denken der Renaissance," 1977-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "Stoic and Neoplatonic Sources of Spinoza's Ethics," 1980-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "Studies of the Classics," 1928 (Box 123)
    - "Studies on Renaissance Humanism During the Last Twenty Years," 1962 (Box 123)
    - "The Study of the History of Philosophy and Its Problems" (Box 123)
    - Tacitus-- Introduction, 1977 (Box 123)
    - "Tasks and Problems of Manuscript Research," 1972-1976 (Box 123)
    - "Thomas More as a Renaissance Humanist," 1975-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "Il Tomismo e il Pensiero Italiano del Rinascimento" (Box 123)
    - "La Tradizione Aristotelica nel Rinascimento," 1962 (Box 123)
    - The Trattati di Lauro Quirin iSulla Nobilite-- Introduction, 1959-1975 (Box 123)
    - "Transcendental and Practical Freedom," 1926 (Box 123)
    - "Two Unpublished Questions on the Soul by Pietro Pomponazzi," 1955 (Box 123)
    - "L'Umanesimo in un Viaggio Informatico," 1966 (Box 123)
    - "Umanesimo Filosofico e Umanesimo Letterario," 1962 (Box 123)
    - "Umanesimo e Scolastica a Padova Fino al Petrarca," 1987 (Box 123)
    - "L'Unita del Mondo nella Filosofia di Marsilio Ficino," 1934 (Box 123)
    - "The University of Bologna and the Renaissance," 1954 (Box 123)
    - "An Unknown Correspondence of Alessandro Braccesi with Nicolo Michelozzi…," 1961-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "An Unknown Humanist Sermon on St. Stephen by Guillaume Fichet," 1962-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "An Unpublished Description of Naples by Francesco Bandini," 1942 (Box 123)
    - "An Uomo di Stato e Umanista Fiorentino: Giovanni Corsi," 1936 (Box 123)
    - Il Ventro Articles, 1980-1984 (Box 123)
    - "Vita Attiva e Vita Contemplativa in un Brano Inedito di Bornio de Sala e in S. Tommaso d'Aquino," 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 123)
    - "Words of Thanks by Paul Oskar Kristeller," 1995 (Box 123)
  - Subseries V.3: Lectures and Speeches, 1940-1993
    This subseries contains lectures, conference papers, and other addresses and presentations given by Kristeller. As Kristeller often gave the same lecture a number of times, the lectures are arranged alphabetically by their title rather than arranged by conference name or date. These files often contain correspondence and conference programs related to conferences where Kristeller spoke.
    - Accademia dei Concordi, 1989 (Box 124)
    - Addresses, 1985 (Box 124)
    - American Historical Association 100th Anniversary Meeting Address,1990 (Box 124)
    - Alberti Conference, 1995 (Box 124)
    - "The Humanist Movement"-- The Arensberg Series of Lectures on the Renaissance, 1956 (Box 124)
    - "Aristotle, Nicomachean Ethics, Books I, II, and X," 1982 (Box 124)
    - "Aristotelian and Non-Aristotelian Elements in Medieval and Renaissance Thought," 1991 (Box 124)
    - "The Aristotelian Tradition and its Opponents" (Box 124)
    - "The Active and Contemplative Life in Renaissance Humanism," 1980-1986 (Box 124)
    - "Der Begriff des Menschen in der Italienischen Renaissance," 1948-1950, (2 Folders) (Box 124)
    - "Byzantine and Western Philosophy," 1970s (Box 124)
    - "Cicero in the Early History of Thought," 1960 (Box 124)
    - "Classical Problems in Modern Philosophy," 1967 (Box 124)
    - Closing Remarks at Marsilio Ficino e il Ritorno di Platone," 1984, (2 Folders) (Box 124)
    - "Il Codice Plimpton 187 Della Columbia Univeristy e Gli Scritti di Lauro Quirini sulla Bibilira," 1968-1971 (Box 124)
    - Columbia College Humanities Lecture Series, 1964 (Box 124)
    - Comments Delivered at 57th Annual Meeting of the American Philosophical Association, 1960 (Box 124)
    - Congresso su Antonio Galateo, 1980 (Box 124)
    - "The Curriculum of the Italian Universities form the Middle Ages to the Renaissance," 1984 (Box 124)
    - "La Diffusione Europea del Platonismo Fiorentino," 1968-1970 (Box 124)
    - "The Early Greek Philosophers," 1946 (Box 124)
    - "The End of the Renaissance in Philosophy and Science," 1961 (Box 124)
    - Europe Lectures, 1989 (Box 124)
    - "The European Diffusion of Italian Renaissance Learning," 1972 (Box 124)
    - "Five Venice Lectures," 1990-1994 (Box 124)
    - "From Augustine to Anselm" (Box 124)
    - "Giuseppe Prezzolini as a Bibliographer and as a Friend," 1983 (Box 124)
    - "Henry Wolfsom's Contributions to the History of Religious Philosophy," 1964-1967 (Box 124)
    - "The Historical Approach to the Philosophy of Mart," 1954 (Box 124)
    - "Humanismus und Scholastik in der Italienischen Renaissance" (Box 124)
    - "Humanism and Philosophy in the Renaissance," 1978 (Box 124)
    - "Humanism, Philosophy, and Science in the Renaissance" (Box 124)
    - "Humanist and Medieval Rhetoric in Italy," 1982 (Box 124)
    - "Die Ideen als Gedanken der Menschlichen und der Goettlichen Vernunft," 1989 (Box 124)
    - "In Memory of Dr. Erla Rodakiewicz," 1965 (Box 124)
    - "In Search of Italian Medieval and Renaissance Manuscripts," 1987 (Box 124)
    - "In Search of Renaissance Manuscripts," 1987-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 124)
    - "Italian Humanism in Eastern Europe," 1958 (Box 124)
    - "The Influence of Renaissance Humanism on the Arts" (Box 124)
    - Introductions (Box 124)
    - "Italian Manuscripts," 1940, 1953 (Box 124)
    - "The Italian Universities of the Renaissance" (Box 124)
    - "Der Italienische Humanismus der Renaissance und Seine Bedeuteng" and "Gelehrte Fraunen Italiendes Mittelalters," 1987 (Box 124)
    - "Latin Schools in the Protestant Tradition," 1986-1987 (Box 125)
    - Lecture Given at Brindisi (Box 125)
    - "A Life of Learning"--American Council of Learned Societies Charles Homer Haskins Lecture, 1990 (Box 125)
    - "Limitations of Linguistic Analysis," 1972-1973 (Box 125)
    - "Man in His Universe in Medieval and Renaissance Philosophy," 1982-1986 (Box 125)
    - "Manuscript Research and Its Problems," 1986 (Box 125)
    - "Manuscript Research on Renaissance Humanism," 1968 (Box 125)
    - "Manuscript Research and Renaissance Thought," 1974-1975 (Box 125)
    - "Marsilio Ficino e il Platonismo del Rinascimento," 1990 (Box 125)
    - 'The Medieval Universities," 1964 (Box 125)
    - "Memorial Service for Edward Rosen," 1985 (Box 125)
    - "Methods of Research in Renaissance Manuscripts," 1974 (Box 125)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1946-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 125)
    - "Movimenti Filisophico del Rinascimento," 1950 (Box 125)
    - "Il Movimento Umanistico," 1962 (Box 125)
    - "Neoplatonism and Islamic Thought," 1982 (Box 125)
    - "Neoplatonism and the Renaissance," 1991 (Box 125)
    - "New Medical Commentaries from Twelfth Century Salerno," 1954-1964 (Box 125)
    - "New Sources on Medicine at Salerno in the Twelfth Century," 1954-1968 (Box 125)
    - "Una Novella Latima e il suo Autore Francesco Tedaldi…" (Box 125)
    - "On Judging Works of the Visual Arts," 1960 (Box 125)
    - "On Learning and Scholarship," 1991 (Box 125)
    - Opening Remarks at Barnard Conference Towards Luther: The Development of Dissent, 1982 (Box 125)
    - "Paduan Averroism and Alexandrism," 1956 (Box 125)
    - "Petrarch's Place in the History of Learning," 1975-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 125)
    - "Philosophical Currents of the Renaissance," 1948-1957 (Box 125)
    - "Philogische Methoden der Renaissanceforschung," 1965-1966 (Box 125)
    - "Philosophical Movements of the Early Renaissance," 1974 (Box 125)
    - "Philosophy and its Historiography," 1985 (Box 125)
    - "The Philosophy of Wladyslaw Tatarkiewicz," 1985 (Box 125)
    - Pisa Lectures, 1990-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 125)
    - "The Place of Ethics in Renaissance Thought" (Box 125)
    - "The Place of Man in Renaissance Platonism and Aristotelianism," 1950-1951 (Box 125)
    - "The Platonic Academy of Florence," 1960 (Box 125)
    - "Il Platonismo Fiorentino e la Tradizione Religiose del Tardo Medio Evo" (Box 125)
    - "Plotinus," 1981 (Box 125)
    - "Pomponazzi and Italian Aristotelianism," 1949 (Box 125)
    - Presentation at Casa Italiana of Giordano Bruno, Oeuvres Complètes, 1993 (Box 125)
    - Remarks Made at Luncheon in Kristeller's Honor-- Pisa, 1986-1987 (Box 125)
    - "Renaissance Aristotelianism," 1956 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Browsings at Columbia and Elsewhere," 1972 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Concepts of Man," 1963 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Education," 1948 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Humanism and Its Lessons," 1980 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Humanism and Classical Antiquity," 1980 (Box 125)
    - "Renaissance Manuscripts in Eastern Europe," 1958 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Philosophy"-- Pisa, 1974 (Box 125)
    - "Renaissance Philosophy and Science in Memory of Charles B. Schmidt," 1987 (Box 125)
    - "Renaissance Platonism," 1973 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Platonism and Its Historical Significance" (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Research in Vatican Manuscripts," 1956-1957 (Box 127)
    - "The Renaissance Society of America and Humanistic Studies in the United States and Canada," 1956-1957 (Box 127)
    - "Renaissance Thought and Christianity," 1985 (Box 125)
    - "Report on my Research Project Concerning the Italian Universities in the Renaissance," 1946 (Box 127)
    - "Research Methods in Intellectual History," 1971 (Box 127)
    - "Rhetoric and Philosophy in the Renaissance," 1978 (Box 127)
    - "La Ricerca Maniscritti Medievali e Umanistici: Metodologia e Risultati," 1989-1994 (Box 125)
    - "Ringraziamento di Paul Oskar Kristeller,: 1984 (Box 125)
    - "The Search for Renaissance Manuscripts," 1980 (Box 125)
    - "Seminar on Spinoza's Ethics," 1973-1974 (Box 127)
    - "Should Classics Departments Include Neo-Latin?," 1972 (Box 127)
    - "The Significance of Salerno's Medical School," 1988 (Box 125)
    - "Society for Textual Scholarship Presidential Address," 1983-1984 (Box 126)
    - "Some New Aspects of Pomponazzi's Doctrine of the Soul," 1953 (Box 127)
    - "Some Problems in the Study of Renaissance Manuscripts," 1969 (Box 126)
    - Speech Delivered at the University of Padova, 1962-1963 (Box 127)
    - Speech Delivered to Montreal Congress of Medieval Philosophy, 1968 (Box 127)
    - Speeches and Toasts, 1963, 1981-1985 (Box 127)
    - "Spinoza, Ethica More Geometrica Demonstrata," 1981 (Box 127)
    - "Studies on Renaissance Humanism During the Last Twenty years," 1958-1962 (Box 126)
    - "Umanesimo e Scolastica a PAdova Fino al Petrarca," 1985-1986 (Box 126)
    - "Viva Attiva e Vita Contemplativa nell'Umanesimo Italiano," 1989-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 126)
    - Taped Lectures, 1974-1987 (Box 126)
    - "Tasks for Future Research in Renaissance Studies," 1983 (Box 127)
    - "La Tradizione Aristotelia nel Renascimento," 1962 (Box 127)
    - "Umanismo e Filosofia nel Rinascimento Italiano", undated (Box 127)
    - "Walter Bust Speech, 1979 (Box 127)
    - Western Lectures, 1951
      - Correspondence (Box 127)
      - Lecture Number One (Box 127)
      - "Ficino and Renaissance Platonism" (Box 127)
      - "Lay Religious Traditions in the Italian Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "Augustine in the Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "The Italian Universities of the Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "Philosophy and Rhetoric in the Italian Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "Latin and Vernacular in the Italian Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "Music and Learning in the Italian Renaissance" (Box 127)
      - "The Origin of the Modern Notion of Art" (Box 127)
  - Subseries V.4: Festschrifts and Memorials, 1978-1993
    This subseries includes articles, lectures, and obituaries given to celebrate or memorialize Kristeller's colleagues.
    - Baron, Salo, 1990 (Box 126)
    - Blau, Joseph (Box 126)
    - Bradner, Leicester, 1988 (Box 126)
    - Bühler, Curt Obituary, 1986 (Box 126)
    - Cataudella, Michele, 1988-1990 (Box 126)
    - Contéssa, 1989 (Box 126)
    - Enugenio, Johannes Scotus, 1974-1976 (Box 126)
    - Fergusion, Wallace K., 1982-1984 (Box 126)
    - Galbiati, Giovanni, 1949-1955 (Box 126)
    - Gilson, 1978 (Box 126)
    - Gordon, Phyllis, 1994 (Box 126)
    - Hirsch, Elisabeth Feist, 1993-1994 (Box 126)
    - Hunt, Richard William, 1990 (Box 126)
    - Kibre, Pearl, 1986-1987 (Box 126)
    - Lee, Rensselaer Wright (Box 126)
    - Marc'hadour, Germain, 1987 (Box 126)
    - Olschki, Leo, 1983-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 126)
    - Pine, Martin, 1997 (Box 126)
    - Prete, Sesto, 1992-1993 (Box 126)
    - Randall, John H. Jr., 1981, (2 Folders) (Box 126)
    - Rosenthal, Bernard, 1990 (Box 126)
    - Salvini, Sebastiano, 1960-1961 (Box 126)
    - Schmidt, Charles, 1986 (Box 126)
    - Trinkaus, Charles, 1991-1993 (Box 126)
  - Subseries V.5: Book Reviews, 1930-1995
    This series is comprised of both reviews of scholarly work written by Kristeller, and other's reviews of Kristeller's own scholarly work.
    - Reviews Written by Kristeller
      - General Reviews, 1955-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 126)
      - Benal's Black Athena, 1994-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 126)
      - Da Cherso, Francesco Patrizi-- Emendatio in Libros suos Novae Philosophae, 1970-1973 (Box 126)
      - Harder, Richard-- Plotius Schriften, 1930 (Box 126)
      - Thieler, Willy-- Die Vorbereitung des Neoplatonismus, 1932 (Box 126)
      - Troje, Hans Erich, 1994 (Box 126)
    - Reviews of Works by Paul Oskar Kristeller, (3 Folders) (Box 126)
- Series VI: Iter Italicum, 1949-1997
  This series is comprised of research notes, manuscripts, and other records related to the Iter Italicum-- the catalog of previously uncataloged or incompletely cataloged Italian humanistic manuscripts, a major work of scholarship that is considered Kristeller's magnum opus.
  - Subseries VI.1: Research, 1949-1986
    The research files are divided into two main sections-- chronological notebooks and country files. The notebooks are Kristeller's notes from his site visits to libraries around the world. The country files include correspondence, manuscript catalogs, and notes. The arrangement of the country files reflects the arrangement of the work as a whole: the files are arranged by country, and by city and then library or institution within each city.
    - Countries
      - Argentina, 1959-1964, 1974-1976 (Box 128)
      - Australia, 1957-1976 (Box 128)
      - Austria, 1958-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 128)
      - Belgium, 1955-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 128)
      - Canada, 1962-1978 (Box 128)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1957-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 128)
      - Denmark, 1961-1979 (Box 128)
      - East Germany, 1957-1981, (5 Folders) (Box 128)
      - Egypt, 1961-1978 (Box 128)
      - England, 1959-1976 (Box 128)
      - England, 1959-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 129)
      - France, 1965-1978, (5 Folders) (Box 129)
      - Germany, 1953-1971, (3 Folders) (Box 129)
      - Great Britain, 1953-1980, (4 Folders) (Box 129)
      - Great Britain, 1953-1980 (Box 130)
      - Greece, 1959-1976 (Box 130)
      - Hungary, Israel, Japan, Lichtenstein, Mexico, 1952-1978 (Box 130)
      - Italy
        - 1949-1961, (6 Folders) (Box 130)
        - 1961-1965, (2 Folders) (Box 130)
        - 1961-1965, (3 Folders) (Box 130)
        - 1966-1972, (2 Folders) (Box 130)
        - 1966-1972, (5 Folders) (Box 131)
        - 1972-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 131)
        - 1972-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 131)
        - 1972-1976, (2 Folders) (Box 131)
        - Discards, undated, 1954, 1974-1981, (4 Folders) (Box 131)
        - Discards, undated, 1954, 1974-1981, (3 Folders) (Box 132)
        - Cities--A to Z, 1957-1980, (5 Folders) (Box 132)
        - Florence, 1949-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 132)
        - Florence, 1949-1964, (4 Folders) (Box 133)
        - Milan, 1952-1962, (2 Folders) (Box 133)
        - Naples, 1952-1962 (Box 133)
        - Rome, 1952-1973, (4 Folders) (Box 133)
        - Vatican City, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 133)
        - Venice, 1950-1964, (2 Folders) (Box 133)
        - Venice, 1950-1964 (Box 134)
      - Netherlands, 1959-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 134)
      - Norway, 1976 (Box 134)
      - Poland, 1952-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 134)
      - Portugal, 1960-1972 (Box 134)
      - Romania, 1958-1965 (Box 134)
      - South Africa, 1960-1961, 1976 (Box 134)
      - Spain, 1952-1978, (7 Folders) (Box 134)
      - Spain, 1952-1978 (Box 135)
      - Sweden, 1958-1977 (Box 135)
      - Switzerland, 1953-1981, (3 Folders) (Box 135)
      - Turkey, undated, 1962 (Box 135)
      - United States, 1951-1979, (8 Folders) (Box 135)
      - United States, 1951-1979, (12 Folders) (Box 136)
      - USSR, 1952-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 136)
      - "Utopia," 1974-1980 (2 Folders (Box 136)
      - West Germany, 1952-1981, (15 Folders) (Box 137)
      - West Germany, 1952-1981, (3 Folders) (Box 138)
      - Yugoslavia, 1958-1979, (2 Folders) (Box 138)
    - Notebooks
      - Content List, 1949-1955 (Box 138)
      - 1949
        - One and Two (Box 138)
        - Three (Box 138)
        - Four and Five (Box 138)
        - Six and Seven (Box 138)
        - Eight and Nine (Box 138)
      - 1952
        - One (Box 138)
        - Two (Box 138)
        - Three (Box 138)
        - Five (Box 138)
        - Six and Seven (Box 138)
        - Eight (Box 138)
      - 1955
        - One and Two (Box 138)
        - Three (Box 138)
        - Four and Five (Box 138)
        - Six (Box 138)
        - Seven and Eight (Box 139)
      - 1958
        - One (Box 139)
        - Two and Three (Box 139)
        - Four (Box 139)
        - Five and Six (Box 139)
        - Seven through Nine (Box 139)
      - 1962
        - One and Two (Box 139)
        - Three and Four (Box 139)
        - Five and Six (Box 139)
      - 1963--One (Box 139)
      - 1966--One and Two (Box 139)
      - 1967--One (Box 139)
      - 1968
        - One (Box 139)
        - Two and Three (Box 139)
        - Four and Five (Box 139)
      - 1969
        - One (Box 139)
        - Two and Three (Box 139)
        - Four and Five (Box 140)
      - 1970--One and Two (Box 140)
      - 1971--One and Two (Box 140)
      - 1972--One (Box 140)
      - 1973--One (Box 140)
      - 1974--One (Box 140)
      - 1975--One (Box 140)
      - 1976--One (Box 140)
      - 1977-1978--One (Box 140)
      - 1979--One and Two (Box 140)
      - 1980--One (Box 140)
      - 1981-1982--One and Two (Box 140)
      - 1983-1984--One (Box 140)
      - 1985-1986--One (Box 140)
      - Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 140)
      - Undated, (8 Folders) (Box 141)
      - Research Notes and Correspondence, 1971-1986, (6 Folders) (Box 141)
      - Research Notes and Correspondence, 1971-1986, (17 Folders) (Box 142)
      - Research Notes and Correspondence, 1971-1986, (16 Folders) (Box 143)
      - Research Notes and Correspondence, 1978-1994, (17 Folders) (Box 144)
  - Subseries VI.2: Editorial and Administrative Files, 1949-1997
    The editorial and administrative subseries is comprised of financial records, grant proposals, publicity material, contracts, and distribution lists related to the editing and publication of the work.
    - Correspondence, 1978-1997, (15 Folders) (Box 145)
    - Contracts and Royalties, 1961-1995 (Box 145)
    - Distribution Lists, 1954-1993, (6 Folders) (Box 145)
    - Financial Records
      - General, 1962-1964 (Box 145)
      - Budget and Fellowship Materials, 1950-1972 (Box 145)
      - Subsidies, 1959-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 145)
      - Grant Applications, 1953-1959 (Box 145)
      - Grant Correspondence, 1957-1981 (Box 145)
      - Grant Narrative (Box 145)
      - American Philosophical Society Grant Material, 1949-1967 (Box 146)
      - Columbia Council for Research in the Social Sciences Grant Correspondence, 1951-1971 (Box 146)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant Material, 1971-1981 (Box 146)
    - Publicity and Reviews, 1958-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 146)
  - Subseries VI.3: Manuscript, 1987-1997